<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autumn | Maximilian Hanusch</title>
    <link>https://maxhanusch.github.io/tags/autumn/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://maxhanusch.github.io/tags/autumn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Autumn</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Maximilian Hanusch 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 20:37:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://maxhanusch.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Autumn</title>
      <link>https://maxhanusch.github.io/tags/autumn/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn in Italy</title>
      <link>https://maxhanusch.github.io/post/lakegarda2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 20:37:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxhanusch.github.io/post/lakegarda2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When temperatures are falling and the first frosts end the vegetation period in the northern Alps, there is still a lot to discover in the Italian part of the mountain range. The mild-climate, a result of the influence of the Mediterranean Sea, invites for hikes until late in the season and allows nature lovers to make some interesting findings.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Papilio.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Papilio.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Caterpillar of a swallowtail, &lt;em&gt;Papilio machaon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Only after a few meters we could already spot the caterpillar of a swallowtail feeding on an umbelliferous plant. Probably this little fellow will not evolve into an imago this year but will instead hibernate as a pupa and serve as the progenitor of next years swallowtail populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our track lead us through the sundrenched southern slope of Monte Pizzocolo. Even though it was already late in the year, we had to start early as the south-exposed trail still becomes a very unpleasant place during the mid-day´s heat. The reflection on the water surface on the one and the heated up rocks on the other side make this part of the trail a furnace, especially during the summer months.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Sunrise.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Sunrise.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;A pittoresque sunrise above Lake Garda&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;








&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Rocks.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Rocks.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Grazing goats keep the vegetation woodless&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The summit welcomes visitors with the pleasure of an amazing view on the lake and the surrounding mountains. The horizon even stretches to the glaciated peaks of the Central Alps in the backgorund. Right below the summit there is a small chapel and a small bivouac site, the Bivacco due Aceri. As the name indicates, it is located between two maple trees and invites hikers to rest and even stay over night.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;View.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;View.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;View from the summit of Pizzocolo&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;








&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Rifugio_join.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Rifugio_join.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;The path to the Bivacco due Aceri and the shelter. Next time we will bring a picnic with us!&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Up at the top we could spot a pink that was still in blossom and brought a glimpse of summer to us. We chose to descend on quite a steep trail that lead along the northern slope of the mountain.  On the way back, we passed through a marvelous deciduous forest mainly consisting of sycamore maple and beech trees.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Dianthus.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Dianthus.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dianthus spec.&lt;/em&gt; greets from the summit&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;








&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Colchicum.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Colchicum.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Colchicum autumnale&lt;/em&gt; showing it´s dainty petals&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;These forests host populations of  my favorite plant, the European Cyclamen. During my undergraduate studies, I was working at the botanical garden in Augsburg. One of my jobs was to clean out the Cyclamen that were propagated there. These overbred flowers in the garden are very sensitive to mold, such as Botrytis, that infects the densely grown flower stalks and the bottom side of the leaves. During the main growing season in late summer and early autumn it was a Sisyphean challenge to keep up with removing old leaves and stalks.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Cyclamenjoin.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;Cyclamenjoin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyclamen purpurascens&lt;/em&gt; growing in a deciduous beech forest&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
